Register to the Papers of Kurt Weill and Lotte Lenya
Yale University Music Library
- Arrangements for Lenya, 1929-1965; Series II; 5.4' (10 boxes)
  - Music by Weill, II.A
    - Operas, Operettas, Musicals, and Ballets, II.A.1
      - [Dreigroschenoper. Barbarasong; arr. Vocal score] Barbarasong., 1 vocal score ([3] p.); 34 cm. (Box 37, Folder 15)
        "Lenya songs" - old envelope.
      - [Dreigroschenoper. Barbarasong; arr. Vocal score] Barbara song: from Threepenny Opera / Weill; Brecht., 1 score (3 p.); 32 cm. (Box 37, Folder 15)
        "Property of Lotte Lenya" - on title page.
        Sketches on back.
      - [Dreigroschenoper. Barbarasong; arr. Vocal score. English] Barbara Song., 1 vocal score (3 p.); 34 cm. (Box 37, Folder 15)
      - [Dreigroschenoper. II. Dreigroschenfinale; arr.], 11 parts; 29-34 cm. (Box 37, Folder 16)
        Manuscript in ink (in part, photocopies) and published parts.
        Miscellaneous parts including piano-vocal (2), alto saxophone/flute/clarinet, tenor saxophone/soprano saxophone/bassoon/clarinet, tenor saxophone, trombone, timpani, double bass, banjo/guitar/bandoneon/violoncello, guitar, and harmonium parts.
        "Extra" - old folder.
      - [Dreigroschenoper. III. Dreigroschenfinale; arr.] No. 20: III: Dreigroschenfinale., 1 part (p. 17-18); 31 cm. (Box 37, Folder 16)
        Incomplete copy of published trumpet I-II part which is crossed out.
      - [Dreigroschenoper. Grabschrift; arr.] No. 19: Grabschrift., 7 parts; 32 cm. (Box 37, Folder 17)
        Includes alto saxophone, bassoon, trumpet, trombone, percussion, harmonium, and piano-vocal parts.
        "German arr." - on old folder.
      - [Dreigroschenoper. Kanonensong; arr.] Kanonen-Song: Dreigroschen-Oper / K. Weill; P. Sandloff., 1 score (18 p.); 34 cm. (Box 38, Folder 18)
        For voice, piano, piccolo, Eb clarinet, alto saxophone, (2), tenor saxophone (2), trumpet (3), trombone (3), tuba, percussion (2 players), banjo, and drums.
      - [Dreigroschenoper. Kanonensong; arr.] Kanonen-Song., 18 parts; 30 cm. (Box 38, Folder 18)
        Includes piano, piccolo, Eb clarinet, alto saxophone I-II, tenor saxophone I-II, trumpet I-III, trombone I-III, tuba, percussion (2), banjo, drums, and engineer's parts.
      - [Dreigroschenoper. Kanonensong; arr.] No. 7: Kanonensong., 1 part ([1] sheet); 32 cm. (Box 38, Folder 18)
        Piccolo part.
        "Extra " - old folder.
      - [Dreigroschenoper, Morgenchoral des Peachum; arr.] Morgenchoral., 1 part ([2] p.); 28 cm. (Box 38, Folder 19)
        Manuscript in ink with pencil sketch for "Polly's Lied" at end.
      - [Dreigroschenoper. Moritat vom Mackie Messer; arr.] Moritat: Dreigroschen-Oper / Musik: Kurt Weill; Arr. Peter Sandloff., 1 score (20 p.); 34 cm. (Box 38, Folder 20)
        For voice and orchestra.
        Duration: 3 min., 10 sec.
      - [Dreigroschenoper. Moritat vom Mackie Messer; arr.] Moritat / arr. P. Sandloff., 9 parts; 33 cm. (Box 38, Folder 20)
        Includes piano, clarinet, trumpet, trombone, tuba, bandoneon/accordion, banjo/guitar, harmonium, and percussion parts.
      - [Dreigroschenoper. Moritat vom Mackie Messer; arr.] Mack the knife: (Lenya)., 1 score (3 sheets); 41 cm. (Box 106, Folder 21)
        For orchestra and voice.
        "Boston-1966 (?)/Partitur in Ab (no parts)" - old envelope.
      - [Dreigroschenoper. Moritat vom Mackie Messer; arr.] Mack the knife: (Lenya)., 9 parts; 32 cm. (Box 38, Folder 22)
        Includes piano/harmonium., alto saxophone, tenor saxophone, trumpet, trombone, banjo (original and copy), double bass, percussion, and harmonium parts.
        "Piano/harmonium 5/9/66 in Gb authentic Berlin arr." - piano part.
        "As done on TV in Boston 5/66" - old folder.
      - [Dreigroschenoper. Moritat vom Mackie Messer; arr.] Mack the knife., 8 parts; 32 cm. (Box 38, Folder 23)
        Manuscript in ink on onionskin (in part, photocopies).
        Includes piano (original and 4 copies), and an original and one copy each of alto saxophone, tenor saxophone, trumpet, trombone, banjo, percussion, and double bass parts.
        "Lotte Lenya/in Ab /no full orchestra score" - old envelope.
      - [Dreigroschenoper. Moritat vom Mackie Messer; arr.] Moritat von [sic] Mackie Messer / Weill; Brecht., 9 parts; 33 cm. (Box 38, Folder 24)
        Manuscript in ink with additions in blue ink (in part, photocopies).
        Includes piano, alto saxophone/soprano saxophone, tenor saxophone, trumpet, trombone bandoneon, banjo (original and copy), harmonium (original and copy), and double bass.
        "In Ab (German arr.) no full score" - old envelope.
      - [Dreigroschenoper. Moritat vom Mackie Messer; arr.] No. 2: Moritat von [sic] Mackie Messer., 6 parts; 32 cm. (Box 38, Folder 25)
        Includes piano, alto saxophone, tenor saxophone, trumpet I-II, trombone, and banjo parts.
        "In Bb /no orchestra partitura" - old folder.
      - [Dreigroschenoper. Polly's Lied; arr.] Mond über Soho., 1 score (11 p.); 34 cm. (Box 38, Folder 26)
        For voice and orchestra [by Peter Sandloff?].
        Duration: 3 min., 15 sec.
      - [Dreigroschenoper. Polly's Lied; arr.] Mond über Soho / arr. Peter Sandloff., 16 parts; 30 cm. (Box 38, Folder 26)
        Includes piano and celeste, flute, oboe, clarinet, tenor saxophone, horn, bandoneon, guitar, harp, timpani, percussion, violin I (6). violin II (4), viola (3), violoncello (2), and double bass (2).
      - [Dreigroschenoper. Salomonsong; arr.] Salomon Song: Threepenny Opera / Kurt Weill., 1 part ([4] p.); 32 cm. (Box 38, Folder 27)
        Manuscript in ink with copies of two pages taped on.
        Hrmn. part.
        "Property of Lotte Lenya" - first page.
        "Lenya key" - old folder.
      - [Dreigroschenoper. Salomonsong; arr.] Salomon song: Accomp. only: Eb., [3] p. of music; 31 cm. (Box 38, Folder 28)
      - [Dreigroschenoper. Salomonsong; arr. Vocal score] Salomon-Song., 1 vocal score ([2] p.); 32 cm. (Box 38, Folder 28)
        "Lenya songs" - old folder.
      - [Dreigroschenoper. Salomonsong; arr. Vocal score. English], 1 vocal score (sheets 19-25); 32-35 cm. (Box 38, Folder 28)
        Words in part, typescript, are given on top of first page.
        Three copies, one copy in folder labelled "Lenya songs."
      - [Dreigroschenoper. Seeräuberjenny; arr.], 8 parts; 32-35 cm. (Box 38, Folder 29)
        Includes piano (5 parts, 4 copies of 1 part), clarinet, clarinet I (2), trumpet, trumpet I (2), trumpet II (2), trombone (2), percussion (2 parts, 2 copies of 1 part), double bass (2 parts, 2 copies of 1 part), and banjo (2 parts, 2 copies of 1 part).
      - [Dreigroschenoper. Seeräuberjenny; arr.] Pirate Jenny., 4 parts; 32 cm. (Box 38, Folder 30)
        Includes clarinet (2), trumpet, trombone, and banjo parts.
        "Tallahassee key" - old folder.
      - [Dreigroschenoper. Seeräuberjenny; arr.] Pirate Jenny., 7 parts; 30-34 cm. (Box 38, Folder 30)
        Manuscript in ink and pencil.
        Miscellaneous parts including piano, clarinet I-II, trumpet I, trombone, percussion, and banjo parts.
        "Extra/German arr." - old cover.
      - [Dreigroschenoper. Zuhälterballade; arr.] Tango-Ballade: (Dreigroschenoper) / Kurt Weill., 1 score (10 p.); 34 cm. (Box 38, Folder 31)
        Manuscript in pencil, title page in ink.
        Arrangement for voice and orchestra [by Peter Sandloff?].
        "British Columbia Record" - old folder.
      - [Dreigroschenoper. Zuhälterballade; arr.] Tango-Ballade / arr. Peter Sandloff., 11 parts; 30 cm. (Box 38, Folder 31)
        Includes flute, oboe, clarinet I, clarinet II, bass clarinet, bassoon, trumpet, percussion, harp, celeste, organ, and engineer's part.
      - [Dreigroschenoper. Zuhälterballade; arr.] No. 12: Zuhälterballade., 3 parts; 29-31 cm. (Box 38, Folder 31)
        Manuscript (photocopy) and 2 published parts.
        Includes piano, alto saxophone/flute/clarinet, and tenor saxophone/soprano saxophone/bassoon/clarinet parts.
        "Different parts (incomplete)" - old folder.
      - [Eternal road. Ruth; arr.] Ruth., 1 score (10 p.); 38 cm. (Box 38, Folder 32)
        Manuscript in ink with red pencil additions.
        "Score and parts O.K. M.L." - on old envelope.
        "Recording" - old envelope.
        "Lenya key" - old envelope.
      - [Eternal road. Ruth; arr.] Ruth., 16 parts; 32 cm. (Box 38, Folder 32)
        Includes piano, flute, clarinet (2), bassoon, horn 1-2, trumpet, trombone, percussion, violin A-C, viola, violoncello, and double bass.
      - [Firebrand of Florence. Sing me not a ballad; arr.] Sing me not a ballad / arr. by Frank Denning., 1 score (8 p.); 41 cm. (Box 106, Folder 33)
        Two copies of above score with spiral binding (41 cm.) laid in.
      - [Firebrand of Florence. Sing me not a ballad; arr.] Sing me not a ballad., 21 parts; 32-36 cm. (Box 38, Folder 34)
        Includes piano-conductor (original and 2 copies), reeds (5: flute, clarinet (2), oboe, bassoon), horn, trumpet (3), trombone (2), guitar, percussion, violin A-D (original and 2 copies), violin B-C (original and 2 copies), viola, violoncello, double bass, harp, and accordion.
      - [Firebrand of Florence. Sing me not a ballad; arr.] Sing me not a ballad., 1 score (28 p.); 35 cm. (Box 38, Folder 35)
        Manuscript in ink with pencil additions and words in blue ink.
      - [Firebrand of Florence. Sing me not a ballad; arr.] Sing me not a ballad., 24 parts; 32-36 cm. (Box 38, Folder 36)
        Includes piano-conductor (original and 3 copies and additions in "short version"), piano, reeds (5), horn (tacet), trumpet I-III, trombone I-II, porc., guitar (tacet), violin A-D, viola, violoncello, double bass, accordion (tacet), and harp (tacet).
      - [Firebrand of Florence. Sing me not a ballad; arr.] Sing me not a ballad., 20 parts; 7 x 23-22 x 25 cm. (Box 38, Folder 37)
        Includes piano, reeds I-V (flute, clarinet, flute, oboe, bassoon ). trumpet I-III, trombone, I-II, percussion, violin A-D, viola, violoncello, and double bass parts.
        'Parts for the short version of "Sing me not a ballad" (in G) (that means: the parts which were cut out!)' - old envelope.
      - [Happy end. Bilbao-Song. Vocal score] Happy end: Komödie mit Musik in 3 Akten von Dorothy Lane / Kurt Weill; Songtexte von Bertolt Brecht... --[Wien]: Universal Edition, c1958., 1 vocal score ([8] p.); 35 cm. (Box 39, Folder 38)
        Photocopy of cut and pasted score for "No. 1. Bilbao-Song" with English words added, as well as additions in ink and red pencil.
        [Pl. no.: U.E. 11685].
      - [Happy end. Bilbao-Song; arr.] Happy end: Nr. 1: Bilbao-Song., 1 score (21 p.); 34 cm. (Box 39, Folder 39)
        For voice, piano, alto saxophone, tenor saxophone, trumpet, trombone, percussion, double bass, banjo, and bandoneon.
      - [Happy end. Bilbao-Song; arr.] Happy end: Nr. 1: Bilbao-Song., 28 parts; 34 cm. (Box 39, Folder 40)
        Includes piano (original and 2 copies), piano-conductor (original and 3 copies), reed 2 (tacet), reed 3 (alto saxophone), alto saxophone (2 different parts), reed 4 (tacet), tenor saxophone (2 different parts), trumpet I-II (tacet), trumpet (3 different parts), trombone (2 different parts), banjo (3 different parts), percussion (2 different parts), violin B-C (tacet), viola (tacet), violoncello (tacet), double bass (2 different parts), and bandoneon.
        "(Philharmonic Concert) N.Y. 11/9/69" - on top of some of the parts.
        "Carnegie Hall 1965" - on old envelope.
      - [Happy end. Bilbao-Song; arr.] Bilbao Song / Kurt Weill., 7 parts; 31 cm. (Box 39, Folder 41)
        Includes alto saxophone, tenor saxophone, trumpet, trombone, double bass, percussion, and banjo parts.
        "(As done in Lincoln Centre) and Dick Cavett Show" - old envelope.
      - [Happy end. Bilbao-Song; arr.] Bilbao-Song, 15 parts - 34 cm. (Box 39, Folder 42)
        Includes solo voice (without words), alto saxophone (2 different parts), tenor saxophone (2 different parts), trumpet (2 different parts), double bass (4 different parts), percussion, and banjo parts.
        With other parts in envelope labelled "German orchestra and piano parts."
      - [Happy end. Bilbao-Song; arr.] Bilbao-Song., 9 parts; 27 cm. (Box 39, Folder 42)
        Manuscript (photocopies, negatives).
        Includes piano, alto saxophone, tenor saxophone, trumpet, trombone, percussion, banjo, harmonium, and unidentified part.
      - [Happy end. Bilbao-Song; arr.] Bilbao-Song / Kurt Weill., 1 score (8 p.); 34 cm. (Box 39, Folder 43)
        Manuscript in pencil, title page signed, in ink.
        For piano, alto saxophone, tenor saxophone, trumpet, trombone, tuba, double bass, banjo, percussion, and harmonium.
        "Bitte nach Des-Dur transponieren."
        In old folder labelled "British Columbia Record."
        1 score (4 p.); 34 cm.
        For solo voice (without words), piano, alto saxophone, tenor saxophone, trumpet, trombone, banjo, and percussion.
        In folder labelled "British Columbia Record."
      - [Happy end. Bilbao-Song; arr.] Bilbao-Song., 10 parts; 30 cm. (Box 39, Folder 43)
        Includes piano, alto saxophone, tenor saxophone, trumpet, trombone, tuba, double bass, banjo, percussion, and engineer's parts.
      - [Happy end. Bilbao-Song; arr.] Bide-a-wee song: Bilbao., 1 part (5 p.); 32 cm. (Box 39, Folder 43)
        Piano-conductor part.
        "Three-penny Opera" [?] - on p. 1.
      - [Happy end. Bilbao-Song; arr.] Bilbao-Song., 1 part ([3] p.); 34 cm. (Box 39, Folder 43)
        "Philharmonic Hall concert 11/9/69" - in pencil on part.
      - [Happy end. Bilbao-Song; arr. Vocal score] Bilbao Song / music by Kurt Weill; English words by Johnny Mercer; original words by Bert Brecht., 1 vocal score (2 sheets); 32 cm. (Box 39, Folder 44)
        Printed (photocopy).
        "This copy is the property of Music Publishers Holding Corp., all rights reserved" - bottom of p. 1.
        In Bb major.
      - [Happy end. Höllenlili; arr.] Happy end: Nr. 12: Die Ballade von der Höllenlili., 1 score (17 p.); 34 am (Box 39, Folder 45)
        Manuscript in pencil with red and green pencil additions.
      - [Happy end. Höllenlili; arr.] Happy end: Nr. 12: Die Ballade von der Höllenlili., 16 parts; 34 cm. (Box 39, Folder 45)
        Includes piano, alto saxophone/clarinet, tenor saxophone, trumpet, banjo, double bass, and percussion parts as well as tacet parts for reeds.
      - [Happy end. Höllenlili; arr. Vocal score. English] Ballade von der Höllenlili = (Lily of Hell): from "Happy end": piano & voice / Weill; Brecht., 1 vocal score (9 p.); 32 cm. (Box 39, Folder 45)
        "For concert (piano only) use accompaniment of verse 1 & 2 " - in pencil on title page.
      - [Happy end. Höllenlili; arr. Vocal score. English] Hoellen Lili / Weill; Brecht-Tabori., 1 vocal score (8 p.); 32 cm. (Box 39, Folder 46)
        Four copies, including one taped together with title page which is marked "Property of Lotte Lenya," and two reverse image copies.
      - [Happy end, Höllenlili. Text. English] Song of the Lily O'Hell: from "Happy end" / music by Kurt Weill., [2] sheets; 28 cm. (Box 39, Folder 45)
        Translation of German by "G. T." [George Tabori?].
      - [Happy end. In der Jugend gold'nem Schimmer; arr.] Happy end: Nr. 7: Heilsarmeelied IV., 1 score (2 p.); 34 cm. (Box 39, Folder 47)
        For voice, alto saxophone, tenor saxophone, trumpet, trombone, double bass, and percussion.
      - [Happy end. In der Jugend gold'nem Schimmer; arr.] Nr. 7., 6 parts; 34 cm. (Box 39, Folder 47)
        Includes alto saxophone, tenor saxophone, trumpet, trombone, double bass, and percussion parts.
      - [Happy end. Kleine Leutnant des lieben Gottes; arr.] Kleine Leutnant des lieben Gottes: reduction in score / Kurt Weill; arr. Paul Sandloff., 1 score (18 p.); 34 cm. (Box 39, Folder 48)
      - [Happy end. Kleine Leutnant des lieben Gottes; arr.] Kleine Leutnant des lieben Gottes: reduction in score / Kurt Weill; arr. Paul Sandloff., 17 parts; 30-33 cm. (Box 39, Folder 48)
        Includes piano, piccolo, soprano saxophone, tenor saxophone, trumpet, trombone, violin I-II (2 copies each), viola (2 copies), violoncello (2 copies), double bass (2), percussion, harp, banjo, harmonium, and engineer's (2) parts.
        "Arr. Peter Sandloff" - on several parts.
      - [Happy end. Lied vom Branntweinhändler; arr.] Happy end: Nr. 8: Das Lied von Branntweinhändler., 1 score (30 p.); 34 cm. (Box 39, Folder 49)
      - [Happy end. Lied vom Branntweinhändler; arr.] "Nr. 8.", 9 parts; 34 cm. (Box 39, Folder 49)
        Includes piano, alto saxophone/clarinet, tenor saxophone, trumpet, trombone, bandoneon, guitar, double bass, and percussion parts.
      - [Happy end. Lied vom Branntweinhändler; arr. Vocal score. English] Lied vom Branntweinhändler = Brandy merchant's song from "Happy end" / Kurt Weill., 1 vocal score (5 p.); 27 x 35 cm. (Box 39, Folder 50)
        Manuscript in ink with words and additions in pencil.
        Positive and negative photocopy laid in.
      - [Happy end. Lied von der harten Nuss; arr.] Happy end: Nr. 11: Das Lied von der harten Nuss., 1 score (8 p.); 34 cm. (Box 39, Folder 51)
        Manuscript in pencil with additions in red, blue, and green pencil.
      - [Happy end. Lied von der harten Nuss; arr.] Happy end: Nr. 11: Das Lied von der harten Nuss., 17 parts; 34 cm. (Box 39, Folder 51)
        Includes piano, alto saxophone, baritone saxophone, trumpet, trombone, banjo, double bass, and percussion parts as well tacet parts for reeds I-II and IV, trumpet II, trombone II, violin A-C, and violoncello.
      - [Happy end. Song von Mandelay; arr.] Song von Mandelay / Weill; Brecht., 1 score (11 p.); 32 cm. (Box 39, Folder 52)
        For voice, piano, alto saxophone, tenor saxophone, trumpet, trombone, banjo, double bass, and percussion.
      - [Happy end. Song von Mandelay; arr.] Mandelay., 16 parts; 32 cm. (Box 39, Folder 52)
        Includes piano, reed 1, alto saxophone, tenor saxophone, reed 4, trumpet I, trumpet II (tacet), trombone I, trombone II (tacet), percussion, violin A-C (tacet), violoncello (tacet), double bass, and banjo.
      - [Happy end. Surabaya-Johnny; arr.] Happy end: Nr. 10: Surabaja-Jonny., 1 score (21 p.); 34 cm. (Box 39, Folder 53)
        Manuscript in pencil with additions in red and green pencil.
        'Key changed to "A" 5/66' - title page.
        Note taped to title page.
      - [Happy end. Surabaya-Johnny; arr.] Surabaya-Johnny., 10 parts; 32 cm. (Box 39, Folder 53)
        Includes voice, piano (original and copy), piano, alto saxophone, tenor saxophone, trumpet, trombone, percussion, double bass, and guitar/banjo.
        Also includes an extra complete set of old parts: alto saxophone, tenor saxophone, trumpet, trombone, bass guitar/Hawaiian guitar/banjo, and percussion.
        "2/24/59 M.L." and "Carnegie Hall 2/7/60" - on old folder.
      - [Happy end. Surabaya-Johnny; arr.] Surabaya-Johnny., 6 parts; 32 cm. (Box 39, Folder 53)
        Includes piano, flute, trumpet, double bass, guitar, and percussion parts.
      - [Happy end. Surabaya-Johnny; arr.] "Nr. 10.", 17 parts; 34 cm. (Box 39, Folder 53)
        Includes piano (original and copy), alto saxophone/clarinet, tenor saxophone, trumpet, trombone, guitar or Hawaiian guitar/banjo or mandolin, percussion, and double bass, as well as tacet parts for reeds 2 and 4, trumpet II, trombone II, violin A-C, viola, and violoncello.
        "Old key (complete)" - note laid in.
      - [Happy end. Surabaya-Johnny; arr.] Surabaja-Jonny / Kurt Weill., 1 score (8 p.); 34 cm. (Box 40, Folder 54)
        "British Columbia Record" - old envelope.
      - [Happy end. Surabaya-Johnny; arr.] Surabaja-Jonny / Kurt Weill., 7 parts; 30 cm. (Box 40, Folder 54)
        Includes piano, tenor saxophone/clarinet, vibraphone, guitar, double bass, percussion, and engineer's part.
      - [Happy end. Surabaya-Johnny; arr.] Surabaya-Johnny / Kurt Weill., 21 parts; 34 cm. (Box 40, Folder 55)
        Includes piano (2), flute, oboe, alto saxophone (2), tenor saxophone (2), clarinet (2), bassoon, horn, trumpet, trombone, violin obbligato, violin, viola, violoncello, double bass, banjo, percussion, and harmonium parts.
        "German orchestration in Eb" - old envelope.
      - [Happy end. Surabaya-Johnny; arr. English] Surabaya Johnny., 19 parts; 25-32 cm. (Box 40, Folder 56)
        Includes piano-voc. (3), alto saxophone/clarinet, tenor saxophone, trombone, guitar or Hawaiian guitar/banjo or mandolin, percussion, and double bass parts as well as tacet parts for reeds 2 and 4, trumpet II (2), trombone II, violin A-C, viola, and violoncello.
      - [Happy end. Surabaya-Johnny; arr. English] Surabaya-Johnny., 1 piano-conductor part (12 p.); 36 cm. (Box 40, Folder 57)
        Manuscript (photocopy) with blue pencil additions.
      - [Happy end. Surabaya-Johnny; arr. Vocal score] Surabaya-Johnny / Kurt Weill., 1 vocal score (2 p.); 34 cm. (Box 40, Folder 58)
        In Lenya's key?.
      - [Happy end. Surabaya-Johnny; arr. Vocal score. English] Surabaya Johnny / music by Kurt Weill; words by Brecht-Tabori., 1 vocal score (6 sheets); 34 em. (Box 40, Folder 58)
      - [Happy end. Was die Herren Matrosen sagen; arr.] Matrosen-Tango: Was die Herren Matrosen sagen / Music: Kurt Weill; Arr. Peter Sandloff., 1 score (8 p.); 34 cm. (Box 40, Folder 60)
        Duration: 2 min., 25 sec.
      - [Happy end. Was die Herren Matrosen sagen; arr.] Matrosen Tango., 16 parts; 30 cm. (Box 40, Folder 60)
        Includes piano, flute I-II, oboe, clarinet I-II, bassoon, accordion, percussion, banjo, double bass, violin I (3), violin II (4), viola, violoncello, and engineer's parts.
      - [Happy end. Was die Herren Matrosen sagen; arr.] Was die Herren Matrosen sagen., 8 parts; 30-34 cm. (Box 40, Folder 61)
        Includes alto saxophone, tenor saxophone, trumpet, trombone, bandoneon, banjo/guitar, percussion, and double bass parts.
        "Low key (highest note b)" - old folder.
      - [Happy end. Was die Herren Matrosen sagen; arr.] Happy end: Nr. 4: Matrosen-Song., 1 score (33 p.) 34 cm. (Box 40, Folder 62)
      - [Happy end. Was die Herren Matrosen sagen; arr.] Happy end: 4. Matrosen Song., 17 parts; 34 cm. (Box 40, Folder 62)
        Includes piano, alto saxophone, tenor saxophone, trumpet, trombone, bandoneon, percussion, and double bass parts as well as tacet parts labelled "Tango" for reeds 1 and 4, trumpet II, trombone II, guitar, violin A-C, viola, and violoncello.
      - [Happy end. Was die Herren Matrosen sagen; arr.] Was die Herren Matrosen sagen / Musik von Kurt Weill; Arrangement von Hartwig v. Platen; Text von Bert Brecht., 24 parts; 34 cm. (Box 40, Folder 63)
        Includes piano-conductor, piano, flute, oboe, clarinet I-II, alto saxophone (2), tenor saxophone, bassoon, horn (2), trumpet I-III, trombone, percussion, violin I (2), violin II, violin oboe, viola, violoncello, double bass, harmonium/accordion, and banjo.
        "German orchestration/original key" - old folder.
      - [Happy end. Was die Herren Matrosen sagen; arr.] Was die Herren Matrosen sagen., 1 part (4 p.); 32 cm. (Box 40, Folder 63)
        "Lenya orchestration" - note laid in.
      - [Happy end. Was die Herren Matrosen sagen; arr.] Was die Herren Matrosen sagen., 1 Part ([7] p.); 34 cm. (Box 40, Folder 63)
      - [Happy end, Was the Herren Matrosen sagen. Vocal score] Was die Herren Matrosen sagen / Kurt Weill; Text von Bert Brecht, - [Wien: Universal Edition], c1929., 1 vocal score (sheets 2-5); 30 cm. (Box 40, Folder 59)
        Photocopy of vocal score published separately.
        Pl. no.: Universal Edition Nr. 9893.
        "Property of Lotte Lenya" - sheet 2.
      - [Happy end. Was die Herren Matrosen sagen; arr. Vocal score (Sketches)] Was die Herren Matrosen sagen., 1 vocal score ([4] p.); 34 cm. (Box 40, Folder 64)